Caleb Ojukwu

https://calebojukwu.vercel.app/ | linkedin.com/in/calebojukwu | caleb.ojukwuu@gmail.com

Summary

Front-end Software Developer for Web and Mobile, with hands on experience using ReactJS, Svelte, Python, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, SQL(Hands on experience with database table design, writing complex SQL queries) and knowledge/experience with phases of a project life cycle. BSc Applied Computer Science.

Software and Technology

Languages & Frameworks: ReactJS, JavaScript, Python, Html5, CSS,

Web: NodeJS

Source Control: Git

Database: SQL, Postgres, MongoDB

Technical Experience

Group Projects

Bone Appetit (Jan - May 2021):

Project Scope: Build a webapp for Bone Appetite, an e-tailer business, selling meal kits for pets(dogs and cats).

Responsibilities:

- Lead a 3-person team consisting of 1 UX designer, 1 business analyst and 1 software developer(me), to deliver a functional MVP without exceeding the \$6000 budget within 3-months.
- Applied all phases of a project life cycle(initiating, planning, executing, and closing).
- Executed 100% of assigned project tasks on time, following best practices (Agile development, test-driven development, continuous integration, and code refactoring.).

Digi Pass (Sept - Dec 2020):

Project Scope: Build a web and mobile payment app called Digi Pass, making it easy for everyone to ride the public transit with just a tap of their smartphone.

Responsibilities:

- Lead a team of 5 consisting of 2 UX designers, 1 Business analyst, and 2 software developers(me), through the design and development process delivering a functional MVP within 4-months.
- Following best practices (Agile development, test-driven development, continuous integration, and code refactoring.).

Travellite(Jan - May 2016):

Project Scope: Create a website called Travellite which is a community marketplace, connecting people looking to host, with travelers looking for accommodations, with over a thousand listings in 10 countries.

Responsibilities:

- Lead a team of 2 consisting of 1 UX designer, and 1 software developer through the development process of the website.
- Delivered a functional MVP within 3-months.
- Followed the Agile development framework in 2-week sprints to develop new features on the product roadmap and resolve bugs.

Personal Projects

Portfolio Website: Caleb Ojukwu

Project Scope: Create a personal portfolio, to display current and future projects, as well as learn the React framework.

- Built using modern technologies such as React, HTML, CSS.
- Deployed using Vercel.

Web Video Player:

Project Scope: Build a simple video player that switches to a mini video player. When the user scrolls down the page, with the option to exit the mini video player while just scrolling.

- Built using modern technologies such as svelte
- Goal of this project is to learn Svelte

WedaForecast: Weda Forecast

Project Scope: Build a weather app that shows the weather for any city in the world.

- Developed using ReactJS, and Open weather API
- Fetched the weather data using Axios
- Deployed using Vercel.

Work Experience

Senior Client Relations Rep

IG Wealth Management

Winnipeg, MB

Oct - Present

Responsibilities:

- Created effortless experiences when receiving and responding to inbound phone and email contacts from consultants, clients, and other institutions, and ensuring we only do what is best for our clients.
- Delivered a reliable, consistent, and transparent service by handling all inquiries with a high level of quality and professionalism, determining the best course of action, and ensuring completion of action has met established standards.
- Deliver value by maintaining knowledge and awareness of all policies, procedures and technologies including sharing information on recent policy changes and simplified business processes.
- Build a culture of quality by assisting team members with problem resolution by providing and sharing information and experiences.
- Helped enabled personal and departmental growth by participating in individual and team meetings with leadership to discuss call monitoring feedback, training and development needs, service levels, and providing feedback on business operation needs and trends by maintaining awareness of business needs and requirements.
- Assisted in fueling our future by supporting transformation and modernization, and promoting adoption for our consultants and our clients as we go through our transformation journey.

• Promoted operational excellence by participating in special projects and assignments within the Client Services

Division

Client Success/Sales Specialist

Winnipeg, MB

7x powered Inc

August - September 2022

Responsibilities:

- Demonstrated ability to effectively implement a consultative and solutions-based sales and/or methodology.
- Thrived in a fast-paced environment and met 100% of the established sales targets.
- Multi-tasked various systems to ensure the clients transaction was completed quickly and accurately.
- Demonstrated the ability to positively influence clients (propose options/solutions).
- Acted as a brand ambassador and provided the clients with a superior experience.
- Communicated a variety of information to clients.
- Actively listened and helped resolve client inquiries, with empathy and understanding creating an effortless experience
- Provided a meaningful and positive experience with every client interaction.

Customer Support

Winnipeg, MB

24/7 Intouch. Dec – Dec 2020

- Approached problems with flexibility and adapted my approach without compromising the outcome and delivering a reliable, consistent, and transparent service
- Assisted all customers through outbound calls.
- Communicated a variety of information to clients.
- Actively listened and helped resolve client inquiries, with empathy and understanding
- Provided a meaningful and positive experience with every client interaction.

Technical support specialist

Aug 2012 - May 2014

MicroLab Tech Warri, Nigeria

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting and resolving client IT problems.
- Tracking and documentation in our internal systems.
- Communicating frequently with the client through phone, email, and in person.

Volunteer Experience
Sound Engineer

The Redeemed Christian Church of God

Winnipeg, MB Jan 2015 - Dec 2018

• Monitored and adjusted audio equipment for maximum performance and sound quality.

- Testing equipment before live broadcasts or recording sessions
- Addressing equipment and software issues.

Education

BSc Applied Computer Science University of Winnipeg

Winnipeg, MB 2015 - 2022